Guide to the Reuben T. Durrett Collection of Lewis Family Papers 1778-1835
University of Chicago Library
- Series I: Legal and Business Documents
  - 1800-1803, Lewis, John, Fredericksburg, Virginia to Gabriel Lewis, Henry Co., Kentucky – Land Grant - February 13, 1801 Lewis, Gabriel - Report of Land Survey - August 1, 1801 Lewis, John, Fredericksburg, Virginia, to Thomas Posey, Franklin Co., Kentucky – Indenture – [January 30, 1802] C., David and Margaret Kerr, [Fredericksburg, Virginia], to Warner Washington Lewis, Fredericksburg, Virginia – Power of Attorney – March 23, 1802 (To complete certain land transactions between them and Henry Massie) C., David and Margaret Kerr, [Fredericksburg, Virginia], to Gabriel Lewis, Fredericksburg, Virginia - Indenture – March 30, 1802 Patton, Robert - List of land plots – April 14, 1802 Lewis, Gabriel, Fayette Co., Kentucky, to Warner Washington Lewis, Spotsylvania Co., Virginia – Indenture – July 7, 1802 Thornton, Anthony to James Madison, Auditor for the State of Kentucky – Letter – October 24, 1802 (Regarding sale of various tracts of land formerly owned by Thornton) Tennent, John, and Sally Tennent, Caroline Co., Virginia, to Gabriel Lewis Fayette Co., Kentucky – Power of Attorney - September 30, 1803 Field, Benjamin to Lawrence Leis - Report of Land Survey - October 5, 1803 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - 1804-1820, Smith, Augustine J. Smith, Fairfax Co., Virginia, to Gabriel Lewis, Kentucky – Power of Attorney – September 27, 1804 Travel journal – 1802- 1805 (Notes of journey from Lexington to Boston, 1802; Fredericksburg to Lexington, 1805; Lexington to New Orleans, 1805) “List of Lands belonging to Reed and Forde in Kentucky” – January 22, 1805 Wingate, J. to Gabriel Lewis – Bill - August 10, 1805 Lewis, Warner Washington – Passport – November 17, 1806 (Signed by James Madison, Secretary of State. With French visa markings) Lewis, Warner Washington – Certification of American citizenship – February 20, 1807 (Signed by George R. Curtis, agent of American Consul General in Holland) Madison, George, Logan Co. Kentucky to John McVicker – Indenture – March 20, 1807 Madison, George to Gabriel Lewis – Receipt – March 20, 1807 (Acknowledging payment by Gabriel Lewis of $230.00 for redemption of certain tracts of lands) Crown Court, Westminster, London to Warner Washington Lewis – Right of Passage – March 26, 1807 (Signed by John Reeves, Superintendent of Aliens) Lewis, Gabriel with Joshua Wilson – Accounts – May, 1805 – August, 1808 George, [W.] and Elizabeth Hopkins, Logan Co., Kentucky, to Gabriel Lewis, Logan Co., Kentucky – Indenture – April 4, 1810 Lewis, John and Thomas Posey – Agreement – October 7, 1814 (Regarding adjustments in earlier land transaction) Personal notebook - 1818-1820 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - 1822-1831, undated, Crittenden, John J., Frankfort, Kentucky to Warner Washington Lewis – March 22, 1830 (Deeding lands in Charlton Co., Missouri) Lewis, Warner Washington, to John U. Waring, Union Circuit Court – Legal Response - June 13, 1831 Lewis, John - Memorandum – undated (On lands in Kentucky) Memorandum – undated (On various land transactions of Robert Patton) Tax Memorandum – undated (Showing amounts paid by various landowners in Knox, Logan, and Main Counties) Barton, Seth to Warner Washington Lewis – Memorandum – undated (Regarding purchase of lands) Lewis, Andrew to Francisco – Memorandum – undated (Regarding instructions for items of legal and financial business) Lewis, Andrew to Woodford Circuit Court – Legal Response – undated (Answer to Bill of John Machis in John Machis vs. Cameron Williams Lewis) Account – undated of Household Goods- undated Personal account book – undated [ca. 1789-1801] (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series II: Correspondence
  - Subseries 1: John Lewis
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence – 1784-1801, Springer, Uriah to John Lewis – May 19, 1784 Neilson, Robert to Henry Crutcher – January 16, 1785 Neilson, Robert to Henry Crutcher – January 26, 1785 Neilson, Robert to Henry Crutcher – March 28, 1785 Brown, George to John Lewis – June 30, 1785 May, John, Petersburg to John Lewis – October 1, 1785 Ewing, Baker, Danville to John Lewis, Fredericksburg – October 25, 1785 Heth, Andrew, Louisville to John Lewis – March 29, 1786 Ewing, Baker to John Lewis – May 8, 1786 Fontaine, Jus to John Lewis, Fredericksburg – April 26, 1790 Crutcher, L.V.H. to Colonel William Fountain – November 15, 1790 Lewis, John to Governor Isaac Shelby – July 1, 1793 T. Posey, Spotsylvania, to John Lewis, Fredericksburg – December 11, 1797 [Momillen] to John Lewis – February 20, 1799 Unknown to John Lewis – March 7, 1800 Lewis, John, Fredericksburg, to the Land Office, Kentucky – May 1, 1800 Unknown to John Lewis, Lexington – September 19, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Subseries 2: Warner Washington Lewis
    - Incoming and Outgoing Correspondence – 1805-1828, For[bes], Standish to W.W. Lewis – January 22, 1805 For[bes], Standish to W.W. Lewis – April 7, 1805 Gazzain, C.W. to W.W. Lewis – July 18, 1825 Mag[enden], Allen to W.W. Lewis – September 1, 1806 Reed[?] to W.W. Lewis – October 25, 1805 Sneed, Achilles to W.W. Lewis – June 10, 1814 Sneed, Achilles to W.W. Lewis – June 25, 1814 Sneed, Achilles to W.W. Lewis – September 23, 1814 Bibb, George M. to W.W. Lewis – July 20, 1821 Crittendon, J.J. to W.W. Lewis – June 14, 1824 Lewis, W.W. to W. Crittendon – October 27, 1828 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Subseries 3: Gabriel Lewis
    - Correspondence with John Lewis – 1799-1801 (Box 1, Folder 9)
    - Correspondence with John Lewis – 1802-1808 (Box 1, Folder 10)
    - Correspondence with Warner Washington Lewis – 1803 - 1831 (Box 1, Folder 11)
    - Incoming Correspondence – 1796-1801, Shaumburgh, B. – April 26, 1796 Wilkinson, James - August 12, 1796 Posey, Thomas – November 15, 1797 Posey, Thomas – August 21, 1799 Posey, Thomas – September 11, 1799 Herndon, William – May 6, 1801 Lattimore, D. – June 8, 1801 Logan, J. – June 15, 1802 Ballinger – June 26, 1801 (Box 1, Folder 12)
    - Correspondence – 1802, Mercer, H.W. – January 5, 1802 Patton, R.W. – February 16, 1802 Ovirton, John – March 2, 1802 Sneed, Achilles – June 25, 1802 Mercer, John – July 7, 1802 Casey, Robert – July 9, 1802 Henderson, David – July 27, 1802 Mercer, John – August 9, 1802 Orr, A. – August 13, 1802 Innes, Harry – August 30, 1802 Mercer, John, and H.T.W. Mercer – September 4, 1802 Posey, Thomas – September 9, 1802 Mercer, H.W. – September 7, 1802 Mercer, H.W. – September 9, 1802 Hughes, J. – October 2, 1802 Thornton, Anthony – October 25, 1802 (Box 1, Folder 13)
    - Correspondence – 1803, [Mobley] and Metcalfe – January 1, 1803 Henderson, D. – January 27, 1803 Tennent, W. – March 16, 1803 Mapie, Henry – April 22, 1803 Maury, Fontaine – May 12, 1803 Arthur, Thomas – August 3, 1803 Mercer, Hugh – October 19, 1803 Ficklin, J. – October 19, 1803 Briggs, D. – November 2, 1803 Scott, Abraham – September 14, 1802 Ballinger, M.O. – March 1, 1803 Gabriel Lewis, Lexington, Kentucky. List (Box 1, Folder 14)
    - Correspondence – 1804, Ridgley, F – January 20, 1804 Smith, August – February 26, 1804 Frazer, William – April 17, 1804 Stevens, Edward – June 6, 1804 Henry Massie – July 10, 1804 Maury, Fontaine – July 18, 1804 Scott, George M – August 4, 1804 Smith, August J. – August. 7, 1804 Smith, August J. – September 18, 1804 Smith, August J. – September 18, 1804 Mercer, Hugh – September 25, 1804. Terrent, John – October 9, 1804. (Box 1, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence – 1805, Herndon, William – January 2, 1805 Craick, William – March 2, 1805 Thornton, Anthony – March 23, 1805 Smith, August J. – July 18, 1805 Woodward, James – August 3, 1805 Posey, Thomas – August 27, 1805 Tennent, William - October 30, 1805 Lewis, William – December 29, 1805 Darby, Adam – January 17, 1805 (Box 1, Folder 16)
    - Correspondence – 1806, Mercer, Hugh – January 6, 1806 Herndon, William – January 30, 1806 Mercer, Hugh – March 9, 1806 Welford – April, 1806 Allen, Thomas – May 11, 1806 Tennent, William – May 29, 1806 Herndon, William – June 24, 1806 Henderson, David – August 12, 1806 Madison, George – September 10, 1806 Askin, Courtney – October 1, 1806 Mapie, H. – November 10, 1806 McVicker, John – November 11, 1806 (Box 1, Folder 17)
    - Correspondence – 1807-1809, Mapie, H. – January 10, 1807 Wallace, W.B. – April 7, 1809 Mapie, H. – April 15, 1807 Tennent, William – August 2, 1807 Mapie, H. – October 19, 1807 Mead, David – December 24, 1807 Mercer, Hugh – March 14, 1808 Logan, John – May 18, 1809 French, G.W. – May 26, 1809 (Box 1, Folder 18)
    - Correspondence – 1813-1835, Carr, Dabney – July 2, 1813 Crittenden, John – January 22, 1820 Macy, A.R. and R. Bibb – January 4, 1828 Unknown – September 15, 1829 Unknown – March 19, 1831 Swigert, P. – July 18, 1833 Morehead, Pousley – February 11, 1835 (Box 1, Folder 19)
    - Correspondence - undated, Taylor, Jonathan Postlethwaite, I. Baston, H.L. (Box 1, Folder 20)